Just like a camera has a lens, so does an enlarger.
And, it is pretty interesting on what these lenses do and what formats these lenses work with.
The lens I am holding in my hand is a fifty millimeter lens.
And, that essentially is a normal lens for this enlarger.
And, you would use this lens when you are making enlargements from a thirty-five millimeter image and if you wanted to just make anything from a five by seven, to an eight by ten, perhaps to an eleven by fourteen.
But, different lenses do different things.
And, these lenses are also very similar to camera lenses is that they have f-stops on them also.
And, just a little bit to understand this, an f-stop on your camera lens controls your depth of field.
The f-stops on these lenses control how much light the lens puts out, and corner to corner sharpness on your print.
I am going to talk a little bit more about that when we get into printing in here, but it is really a very important thing to know that different formats take different lenses.
So, this is a fifty, a normal lens for printing thirty-five millimeter.